All right! Chores are done.
好了！家务做完了
Now can we do some dune bashing?
现在能去玩沙丘赛车吗？
I don't know, Miko.
我没想好 神子
Last time I spent a week picking sand out of my articulators.
上次我花了一个星期去清理发声器里的沙子
But there is a monster truck rally in town...
不过市里有个大脚车拉力赛…
Optimus, I'm receiving a signal of our restricted band.
擎天柱 我收到一个来自秘密波段的信号
It appears to be coming from a starship inside the solar system.
好像来自一艘宇宙飞船 就在这个太阳系内
It's an Autobot identification beacon.
是一个汽车人的标识信号
So there are other bots out there?
还有其他的汽车人吗？
The masses scattered to the galaxies when Cybertron finally went dark.
塞博特恩陷入死寂的时候 很多人都流落到太空
But, cons have been known to bait traps with false beacons.
不过 虎子们经常用假信号当作诱饵
Unknown vessel, this is Autobot outpost Omega One.
不明飞船 这是汽车人前哨基地欧米加1号
Identify yourself.
表明你的身份
I've had warmer welcomes from Decepticon combat brigades.
霸天虎作战部队的欢迎仪式 可比这热闹多了
Wheeljack?
千斤顶？
You old Con-crusher!
你这打虎子老手！
What do you do all the way out here?
你大老远跑这儿来干嘛？
Bulkhead? That's you!
隔板？是你！
What's with all the security?
怎么那么多的安全措施？
The rock we are on is crawling with Cons.
我们住的这块大石头上爬满了虎子们
How soon can you get here and even the odds?
你什么时候过来？我们正缺人手
Sometime tomorrow, but put metal to the pedal.
明天的某个时刻 但我得踩踩油门
Another bot's coming here?
又来了个汽车人？
How cool is that?
这可太酷了！
Wheeljack,
千斤顶…
I know of him by reputation only.
我只听说过他的大名
Can you verify his voiceprint?
你确认是他的声纹吗？
He is one thousand percent the real deal, Optimus.
百分之一千是他 擎天柱
We will send landing coordinate, Wheeljack.
我们会提供着陆坐标 千斤顶
Safe journey.
祝旅途平安
See you soon buddy.
到时候见 哥们儿
I'll make sure you get a proper welcome.
我给你准备个隆重的欢迎仪式
So who is the boyfriend?
你这朋友什么来头？
We were part of the same war unit ¨C
我们曾经并肩战斗在…
¨C the Wreckers,
雷霆救援队
which means the cons are gonna wish he never found us.
虎子们碰上我们 只能有来无回！
"Wheeljack? What do you do all the way out here?"
“千斤顶？你大老远跑这儿来干嘛？”
"Bulkhead? That's you."
“隔板？是你！”
"What's with all the security."
“怎么那么多的安全措施？”
"The rock we are on is crawling with Cons."
“我们住的这块大石头上爬满了虎子们”
A war hero, mh?
来了个战斗英雄 嗯？
We haven't much time.
我们要抓紧时间
Makeshift!
千面客！
"The rock we are on is crawling with Cons."
“住的这块大石头上爬满了虎子们”
"How soon can you get here and even the odds?"
“你什么时候过来？我们正缺人手”
"Sometime tomorrow, but put metal to the pedal."
“明天的某个时刻 但我得踩踩油门”
"See you soon buddy."
“到时候见 哥们”
"I'll make sure you get a proper welcome."
“我给你准备个隆重的欢迎仪式”
I do know how to prepare and proper welcome.
我也会准备一个隆重的欢迎仪式
Wheeljack ship is approaching the landing zone.
千斤顶的飞船正接近着陆区
You think he¡¯s here to visit?
他只是碰巧路过吗？
Maybe he'll stay!
说不定会留下来呢！
Hmm, have to find his own human though.
嗯 但得给他找个人类同伴
Ground Bridge cycling up.
环陆桥开始运行
The equipment hasn't been the same since the infestation.
自从上次被侵蚀后 设备便大不如前了
So Wheeljack is gonna land half way around the world,
就是说 千斤顶将在地球的另一面着陆
and then you'll bridge him here?
然后你再把他接过来？
We can't risk revealing the location of our base,
我们基地的位置要保密 不能冒险
just in case the Decepticons are tracking Wheeljack's ship.
这是为防止霸天虎跟踪千斤顶的飞船
Dude, I've never seen you so stoked.
哥们 我从没见过你这么兴奋
Ho, you're gonna love Wheeljack.
噢 你会喜欢上千斤顶的
We were like brothers!
我们亲如手足！
And tonight, we are gonna party!
今晚我们要好好乐乐！
S-weet!
好棒啊！
Bogies,
麻烦来了
closing fast on Wheeljack's position.
正向千斤顶的方位迅速接近
Con-scum!
这群虎崽子！
If you are trying to ruin my day,
如果你们想扫我的雅兴
you are gonna have to try harder.
可得加把劲了
You Cons have gone soft on me.
一群温顺的小猫
Swiftly, before the Autobots arrive!
快点 要赶在汽车人到达之前！
Open the bridge, Ratchet. We're missing all the action.
把桥打开 救护车 我们要错过好戏了！
I¡¯ll prepare sig-bay.
我去准备医疗舱
Hehe, who for? The Cons?
给谁准备？虎子们？
This is Wheeljack we are talking about.
他可是响当当的千斤顶啊
Ever think I might need a hand here?
以为我会需要增援吗？
What? And spoil the show?
啥？去糟蹋一场好戏？
You missed one.
你漏了一个
If this is all you get,
如果你们就这么几个人
the planet is in bigger trouble than I thought.
这星球的情况可比我想像得要糟
Jackie! Hahahahaha...
老千！
Jacky, come here.
老千 过来
Meet my other best buddy, Miko!
这是我另一个死党 神子！
She can wreck with a best of us.
她的实力跟咱俩不相上下
Hi ya.
你好
You keeping Bulkhead out of trouble?
你好好看着隔板 别让他找麻烦
I try.
我会的
But trouble finds us anyway.
但麻烦总是主动找上门来
We are gonna get along just fine.
我们会相处融洽的
Optimus Prime.
擎天柱
It's a privilege.
久仰大名
Likewise, soldier.
彼此彼此 战士
What have you to report from you long journey?
你远道而来 有什么发现？
Been bouncing from rock to rock,
从一个星球到另一个星球
searching for signs of friend or foe.
寻找朋友和敌人而已
Now, I find both.
现在 两样都找到了
We are few, but strong.
我们人少 但都是精锐
We have suffered losses,
我们失去过同伴
but we have grown.
但也得到了教训
And we would relish welcome in a new member into our fold.
我们也非常欢迎新成员的加入
I would be honored.
我感到荣幸
Then let's get this party started!
那就开始狂欢吧！
Oh, joy!
真是乐疯了
The moment Makeshift passed through that Ground Bridge
千面客穿过环陆桥的那一刻
we lost his tracking signal.
我们就失去了他的追踪信号
The Autobot base is no doubt heavily shielded to
汽车人基地看来的确守卫森严
prevent us from locating it.
我们难以摸清它的位置
No matter,
不过 没关系
I have complete faith in Makeshift.
我对千面客有绝对的信心
Our inside man is already inside.
我们的卧底已经打入了他们内部
Tell Megatron he's fragged in the head if he thinks
告诉威震天 如果他觉得隔板认不出那个冒牌货
Bulkhead won't sniff out an impositor.
那他的脑子就有问题了
Haven't you heard, I lead the Decepticons now.
你还不知道吗 霸天虎现在由我统领
You? Hah!
你？哈！
Yes! Yes... He may yet be of use.
是的 他可能还有利用价值
Makeshift is very good at keeping up appearances.
千面客很擅于伪装
He need only fool your friends long enough
他只需骗过你的朋友们
to open their Ground Bridge from within.
然后从内部打开环陆桥
So that I may finally learn the location of the Autobot base.
那样我就能知道汽车人基地的位置了
And send in my strike team to
接着 我派出的突击队
stain its floor with the spilled energon of Optimus Prime.
会让擎天柱体内的能量洒遍整个基地
Come on, Jackie. Show me what you get.
来吧 老千 让我看看你的能耐！
So, what's that about?
那是什么？
It¡¯s called Lobby,
那叫抛球
the favorite past time on Cybertron,
塞博特恩上最受欢迎的消遣项目
especially among warrior class.
特别是对于勇士阶级
Come on, Raf! Show us some moves.
来吧 拉夫! 让我们看看你的舞姿
Oh, alright.
哦 那好吧
Where is Optimus?
擎天柱呢？
Went for a drive.
兜风去了
Primes don't party.
领袖们不参加派对的
Coming at you! Yew!
冲你来了！
You know what? I am attempting to perform sensitive calibrations here!
你们知不知道 我正在进行精确的校准工作！
Sorry, doc.
抱歉 大夫
Guess we are a little charged up.
看来我们有点兴奋过头了
You built this bridge from scratch, huh?
整座桥都是你建的 对吧？
I did.
是的
That¡¯s quite a feat of engineering.
这的确是个庞大的工程
Yes it is.
是的 没错
Something wrong with it?
出问题了吗？
I didn't care for the way it sounded of this last jump.
上次运作时的响声听起来不对劲
I put it in shutdown.
我把它关掉了
What if you need to use it?
那需要用的时候怎么办？
Woo... I can't disrupt the defrag process without causing unreparable damage.
喔 中断磁盘整理程序会造成不可修复的损坏
So uh... How long would the defrag take?
那…磁盘整理程序需要多久？
A few hours, if we are lucky.
如果幸运的话 几小时吧
Maybe longer.
也可能更久
Makeshift still hasn't open their Ground Bridge,
千面客还没有打开他们的环陆桥
or otherwise transmitted their coordinates.
或传送他们的坐标
His disguise may be flawless,
尽管他伪装得天衣无缝
but he won't fool the Autobots forever!
但他不可能把汽车人一骗到底！
So there we were, no communications,
当时我们在那里 通讯失灵
low on energon, surrounded by Cons.
能量不足 被虎子们包围
So what does wheeljack do?
猜猜千斤顶是怎么干的？
Well, what I do best.
当然是我最拿手的！
He chucked his only grenade and smacked into the primary heat exchanger.
他拧开唯一的一颗手雷塞进了主换热器
Yea, seem like a good idea at that time.
是啊 当时看来这主意不错
The joint went supernova!
整个区域像超新星爆发一样
Awesome...
帅啊…
Yea, I'm still picking shrapnel out of my back side.
是啊 现在都还能从我背上找出弹片呢
I'm not surprised,
我不觉得惊讶
given the size of your back side.
就冲你那背部的体积
There is it, Jackie signature.
于是乎 老千有了个外号
One grenade, one shot.
“一颗手雷闯天下”
Hey, you are alright?
嘿 你没事吧？
What?
怎么？
You don't seem like yourself.
你好像有些反常啊
What do you mean?
你这话什么意思？
I dunno you seem, quiet.
我不清楚 你似乎过于沉默了！
Ah, I've been stuck in a can too long.
在罐子里呆得太久了
I should go top side before I get stern crazy.
在我疯掉之前 出去透透气吧
I have patrol in the morning. You can come with.
我早上有巡逻任务 你可以一起来
Let's go now.
我们现在就去吧！
And break up the party?
让派对不欢而散？
Come on. The gang's loving you.
拜托 他们多喜欢你啊！
You got to tell about the Battle of Dark Mount Pass.
去讲讲在暗峰山的战斗
You'll tell them. You're better at it.
你去吧 讲故事你在行
How about if Miko here shows me the rest of your base.
不如让神子带我逛逛你们的基地吧
Well, yea. Sure, Jackie. Go ahead.
啊 当然可以 老千 去吧
Tour starts now.
参观现在开始
Do you play any instruments?
你懂乐器吗？
Can you fly? Have you thrust  more Decepticons than Bulkhead?
你能飞吗？你揍过的霸天虎比隔板还多吗？
You alright?
你没事吧？
Yea. Just, out of thoughts I guess.
没事 只是…有点走神罢了
Don't tell me you're... jealous.
别告诉我 你…妒忌
That Miko's making a new friend? Come on.
妒忌神子交到新朋友？怎么会呢
Something,
只是…
something is just not right about Wheeljack.
只是感觉千斤顶有些不对劲
Bulkhead, really.
隔板 想想看
He's travelled galaxies.
他走过那么多星系
You haven't ever seen him for centuries.
你们几个世纪没见了
He could just be rocket lagged.
他可能有点太空时差
Well, bots do change, you know?
你也知道 汽车人也是会变的
Not Jackie.
老千不会的
You are not going anywhere, Autobot.
你哪儿也走不了 汽车人
Blablabla...
废话真多
So that's pretty much it.
基本上就是这些
Energon stock pile, power generator, armory,
能量堆 发电机 军械库
everything you need to blow the joint sky high.
都是可以用来玩大爆炸的
Where is this bunker located, exactly?
这个堡垒具体在哪里？
If I told you,
如果我告诉了你
I'd have to rip out your spark chamber.
我就得把你的火种室扯出来！
Kidding!
开玩笑的！
Just outside Jasper in Nevada.
就在内华达州的贾斯帕市郊区
Though I don't expect that'll mean much to you.
虽然我不觉得对你有什么用处
Can't say it does.
说不定有用…
So, eh, anyway out of here besides bridging?
那 除了过桥 还有其他出路吗？
Why?
问这干嘛？
You¡¯re not planning to leave already, are you?
你不会是打算要走吧？
Come on, I'll show you.
来吧 我带你过去
Almost there.
差不多了
Look, I know Wheeljack better than anyone.
听着 我比任何人都了解千斤顶
I was just telling the guys all about you and me, at the Battle of Dark Mount Pass.
我刚才在跟他们讲我们在暗峰山的战斗
That¡¯s a heck of the story.
那故事可精彩了！
Yep. Tell it.
没错 讲来听听！
Talk, talk, talk. How about after we go off roading?
讲 讲 讲 等我们兜完风后再讲吧？
Miko, stay out of this.
神子 这不关你的事！
Bulkhead, easy.
隔板 别这样
I'm not sure I...
我看没必要…
Tell it!
讲！
Fine. You want to live in the past, Bulkhead.
好吧 既然你要重温过去 隔板
The Wreckers were trapped between an Decepticon patrol and the melting pit.
雷霆救援队困在了一队霸天虎巡逻队和熔炼坑之间
The cons were vicious,
虎子们凶猛无比
bearing down on us with everything they had.
我们被完全压制了
Me and Bulkhead engaged the enemy,
我和隔板与敌军一番大战
left them for scrap,
把他们变成了废渣
then I made us a way out,
然后我杀出一条血路
using their backsides as stepping stone to cross the melton metal.
踩着他们的后备箱 跳过了熔炼坑
Is that how it happened?
不就是这样吗？
Yea,
没错
that's exactly how it happened.
的确就是这样
Except for one little thing,
除了一个小细节
I wasn't there.
我并不在场！
What?
什么？
I'd already left the Wreckers to join up with Optimus.
我当时已经离开雷霆救援队 追随了擎天柱
But you wouldn't know that if all you did was access Wheeljack's public service record.
只看千斤顶的公开服役记录 你是不会知道的
Bulkhead, what is that have to do with.. Oah...
隔板 那些事跟这有什么…噢！
Miko!
神子!
Stay back. Or I'll squeeze her into pulp.
别过来 否则我把她捏成肉泥！
Wheeljack, what are you doing?
千斤顶 你在干什么？
Decepticon coward!
霸天虎懦夫！
Let the girl go and face me.
把女孩放了 我才是你的对手！
Don't fret,
别心急
plenty of fighting to come.
接下来的仗够你打的
Is there a real Wheeljack?
到底有没有真的千斤顶？
Oh indeed.
当然有
And I expect lord Starscream is making sport of him.
我估计红蜘蛛陛下正拿他找乐子呢
Are you certain we are at the coordinates you supplied to makeshift?
你肯定千面客收到你给他的坐标了吗？
Then what is taking him?
那他还磨蹭什么？！
Maybe they give your boy such a hero's welcome.
你们的人也许受到了英雄般的欢迎
He got the warm and fuzzies and decided to switch sides.
他受到感召 所以弃暗投明了
Do you not see that you are vastly out-numbered?
你不觉得你在以寡敌众吗？
I see fellows who might bestly enjoy watching me pumps up dints into you.
他们是观赏我在你身上打洞的最好观众！
Eh, destroy him!
干掉他！
About time!
到时候了！
Well, well.
瞧啊 瞧啊
Let's get this party started!
让派对正式开始吧！
I'd shut that hole before the stinks come through.
如果是我 就会在那些臭虫进来之前把洞封上
Enter the Ground Bridge now!
立即冲进环陆桥！
Ugly is mine.
脏活儿让我来！
Which one is the real Wheeljack?
哪个是真的千斤顶?
Eh, I lost track!
哎呀 我分不清了！
That's my Jackie.
那才是我的老千！
You, hit the switch.
你 按下开关
It's time to take out the trash.
是时候清理垃圾了
All yours, buddy.
全归你了 哥们
What are you waiting for? Go!
你们还在等什么？去啊！
Nice lob!
好球！
Please, tell me that you at least learned the location of their base!
告诉我 至少你知道他们基地所在的位置！
Indeed, lord Starscream.
当然 红蜘蛛陛下
It is in a hidden bunker, just outside of...
它在一个隐秘的碉堡里 就在靠近…
Wow! Back, back, back!
哇！后退！后退！后退！！
Oh no.
噢 不！
Makeshift, you fool!
千面客 你这蠢货！
It's like a recurring nightmare.
就像一个不断循环的噩梦
Now that you're part of Team Prime.
现在你是领袖卫队的一员了
We need to pick out a vehicle mode for you.
你得选择一个伪装形态
I have some ideas.
我有个建议
Uh, about that, Bulk.
嗯 关于那个 小隔
Now that my ship's repaired.
现在我的飞船修理好了
I'm itchy to know, what else I might find out there.
我很感兴趣 对于外面世界的未知力量
Wait, you're leaving?
什么 你要离开？
Why?
为什么？
Wheeljack, know that you always have a haven here.
千斤顶 记住 这里永远是你的港湾
Jackie never stays.
老千从不原地踏步
But he always comes back.
但他总会回来的
There's room for two, Bulk.
这里能坐下两个人 小隔
Even with a backside like yours.
即使你的背部再大也不成问题
Who knows who we might find out there?
谁知道在外面会找到什么呢？
Some of the old crew?
一些老战友？
But my ties are here now,
但我已经心有所属
with them,
跟他们
with her.
还有她
If anything happens to my favorite wreker,
如果我最要好的队友出了什么岔子
I'm coming after you.
我绝不会放过你
I'll take good care of him.
我会好好关照他的！
Now, say Cheese!
现在 笑一个！